NASA is trying to split atoms in space
to power a [music] ship. So, right now,
we mainly move spacecraft by burning
fuel and shooting out the gas created in
that chemical reaction. But, bringing
all that fuel and the oxygen to burn it
is really heavy. [music] So, they've
tested more efficient engines that shoot
out electrically charged gas, but those
rely on solar panels, which get less
efficient the further you travel from
the sun. So, NASA wants to power these
engines by doing nuclear fission in
space. Same thing we do in nuclear power
plants on Earth. Nuclear energy creates
10 to 100 times more power than solar,
meaning we could get places faster, and
we could also travel farther if we're
not constrained by the sun. So, NASA's
planning to test this on an upcoming
mission to Mars. To [music] see it,
subscribe.